# Sonyah G. Seiden New York, NY

<u>LinkedIn</u> • <u>GitHub</u> <u>sonyahseiden@gmail.com</u> +1.808.398.0030

# Impact-oriented team leader bringing 5 years' experience overhauling data & reporting infrastructure, 2 years managing analysts & engineers.

Expertise pooling & transforming distributed, high-cardinality data into scalable frameworks for multiple stakeholders.

#### **Skills**

## **Programming Languages**

- Year of experience
- · · · · SQL
- •••• Python
- •• Regex, Git
- graphQL

#### **Tools**

Viz: Tableau, PowerBI

*IDE:* VSCode, Jupyter, Postman *Other:* Jira, Confluence, Notion

#### Other

Building stakeholder trust, Cross-team communication, Delegation, Pacing productivity

#### **Education**

Franklin University CH B.A., Honors in

**Art History & Economics ('16)** 

Magna cum laude, 3.69 GPA

#### **Extra Curriculars**

Statistics Department Tutor

Resident Assistant

**Merit Awards** 

Lifelong Learning Scholar Franklin Scholar

**General Assembly** 

Audit, Intro to JavaScript

**Cert. Product Management** 

50 hours on PDM theory *Instructor Sponsorship* 

**Data Science Fellowship** 

300 hour bootcamp on Python *Opportunity Fund Scholar* 

Cert. Data Analytics

50 hours on SQL & Tableau

# **Professional Experience**

## **General Assembly**

May - Dec 2020 - 2023

#### **Contract Instructor**

Avg. Instructor Rating: 4.7/5

- Instructional Associate: <u>Data Science</u> (Python) Intuit, BAH, PayPal, Barclays, WPP, Consumer
- Lead Instructor: <u>Data Analytics</u> (Excel, SQL, Tableau) BAH, Consumer

#### **Kroll Bond Rating Agency**

Apr - Apr 2022 - 2023

## Product Owner (Technical), Ratings DB

- Pitch & manage overhaul of PowerBI data pipelines
- Formalize business logic within Python objects, ETL library, and denormalized Snowflake DB
- Ticket & QA internal client APIs (Rest, GraphQL)
- Setup & update external client feed configurations
- Ticket turnaround reduced by 30% through improved ticket management on Jira
- Report weekly, quarterly KPIs for internal APIs

## R2Net, Inc. - James Allen.com

June - July 2020 - 2021

# **Business Intelligence Manager**

- Hire, train, supervise three analysts for Ops, BI team
- Design reporting ETL infrastructure reducing report lead times up to 90%
- Increase team productivity by 35% with SCRUM
- Write SQL queries & draft processing pipelines
- Pool data from SQL db, Rest & graphQL APIs
- Modularize Python data processing scripts
- Collaborate with COO, CTO & Product Managers

Aug - June 2019 - 2020

Oct - Aug

2018 - 2019

# **Senior Operations Analyst**

- Hire & train two analysts for Ops team
- Automate data processing for Ops & Merchandising
- Standardize monthly and quarterly sales dashboards
- Manage team documentation, GitLab, and Jira

# **Operations Analyst**

- Script department cleaning procedures in Python
- Automate processing & imputation improving daily sales report data integrity by 40%
- Report bugs and data errors, draft feature requests for store backend and sales management applications

Hobbies: painting, visiting museums, backgammon, reality tv